

# Malavika Pedinti

DATA SCIENCE MANAGER

#### **PROFILE**

Over 11 years of experience in deriving insights from data through business intelligence and data science to enable businesses make intelligent decisions. Worked both individually and led large data science teams, successfully achieving the project goals

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

#### **Address**

C. V. Raman Nagar, Bangalore, India

#### CONTACT

- malavika.287@gmail.com
- 9916473247
- in malavika-peedinti

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Science Manager

BLP INDUSTRY.AI Apr 2018 - Current

organisation, including renewable energy, oil and gas, airports, seaports, smart buildings and manufacturing industries

o Collaborate with tech partners to formulate the business use case and design and deploy

o Responsible for execution and delivery of analytics across all the operational verticals in the

o Collaborate with tech partners to formulate the business use case and design and deploy machine learning systems in *Google Cloud Platform*, in coordination with Data engineering and Application teams

- o Range of business use cases solved encompass **predictive maintenance** of machines, **optimization** of process parameters to production, **vibration analysis** and **electrical signature analysis** of critical components in machines, curbing **wake effect** in wind farms with irregular layouts, **recommending** optimal cleaning cycle for solar panels in utility scale power plants
- o Research and analyse data sets using a variety of statistical and machine learning techniques
- o Validate the assumptions made for developing the models, code reviews and model results
- o Perform code reviews and dashboard reviews
- o Coaches, mentors and influences others to accomplish departmental goals
- o Works to maintaining a friendly and collaborative work environment

#### Data Consultant

**SYNTEL PVT. LTD.** Nov 2015 - Feb 2018

o Created crisp visualizations in Tableau to showcase organisation wide information o Use SQL queries to perform design and quality validations on massive data warehouses o Implemented PoCs on prediction of loan repayment and marketing campaign outcomes

#### Data Engineer

**INFOSYS** Oct 2009 - Oct 2015

o Test the data warehouse design and ETL jobs for major banking clients through optimized and customised SQL queries

o Perform Data Quality Assurance and data profiling

## EDUCATION

# Data Science

INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, BANGALORE

2015

BE, Instrumentation Engineering

SIDDAGANGA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, TUMKUR

2005-2009

## MACHINE LEARNING SOLUTIONS

Anomaly Detection Failure Prediction Time Series Analysis Forecasting

Recommendation Optimization

## **TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES**

SQL Python R Tableau Grafana Teradata GCP Influx DB

## SKILL SET



## CONFERENCES AND PUBLICATIONS

- Talk on 'Machines Talk, Machines Learn' at RISING 2020 by Analytics India Magazine
- Presentation on 'Algorithm to correct yam misalignment in wind turbines' at Machine Learning Developers Summit 2020 by AIM
- Presentation on 'Cloud for Climate' at grace
  Hopper Celebration India 2019
- Platinum Category Award winning white paper on 'Overcoming Challenges faced in data warehousing' at Infosys in 2010
- Presentation at International Science

  Congress on 'Mining and Manufacturing on Moon' at ISRO in 2008

# PATENT

Co-inventor of a patent pending algorithm designed to 'Recommend the optimal

cleaning cycle of photo voltaic panels in a utility-scale solar power plant', filed in Nov 2019 at Indian Patent Office, bearing application number 201941047730